<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-02T13:10:01-07:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jim Mitchell</title><subtitle>Thoughts, Stories and Code</subtitle><author><name>Jim Mitchell Media</name></author><entry><title type="html">Seeing The Forest For The Trees</title><link href="/2019/12/10/seeing-the-forest-for-the-trees/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seeing The Forest For The Trees" /><published>2019-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/2019/12/10/seeing-the-forest-for-the-trees</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/12/10/seeing-the-forest-for-the-trees/">&lt;p&gt;No matter how well-intentioned we are, sometimes we allow things to sneak into our lives under the guise of it being something important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ask “&lt;em&gt;Who else can do this?&lt;/em&gt;” Or maybe we tell ourselves “&lt;em&gt;No one else is qualified enough, so I’m the one who has to do it.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we start thinking like this, it’s our ego calling the shots. Maybe we want to be the hero, or we worry those who needed us in the past no longer will and that we won’t be their go-to person anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our ego persuades us take on more and more, forcing us to say yes when our heart is telling us we should be saying no. Before we know it, the commitments have piled up on us again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wake up one day and realize we’ve allowed so many things back into our lives that we dread getting out of bed and facing them. We’re over-committed again and can no longer see the forest for the trees in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this happens to me, I make a day of solitude away from distractions and reflect on how I got to this point again. Then I figure out what I need to do to get life back on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I accept I won’t always be able to say no when I should. The only thing I can do is learn from caving in to my ego and grow from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m stretched thin, these are some of the things I do to start cutting out the commitments that I should have said no to from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whos-affected&quot;&gt;Who’s Affected?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ask myself who’s affected most?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, the person I’ll be letting down will be disappointed, but I ask myself who else has been neglected because I have so much on my plate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually it’s my family that suffers most when I allow distractions. It’s easy to forget these are the important relationships to nurture. They’re the ones that are always the closest, so it’s easy to put them on the back burner. I learn more and more when I overcommit that I should be guarding these relationships fiercely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only does my family suffer, but so does my health. I end up having so much going on that I don’t get proper sleep, exercise and I don’t eat well enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I wind up feeling burnt-out on life as a whole and get cranky with everyone around me. The most important relationships have wound up paying the price because I said yes when I should have said no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-someone-else-do-it&quot;&gt;Can Someone Else Do It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to let go of my ego and turn the work over to someone else who can do the job just as well as I would have, if not better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remind myself I’m not the only person in the world who has the talents to tackle a particular project. In fact, there may even be someone else who’s much more qualified than I ever was. This helps to remind me it’s okay to step aside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might even be good to let someone who isn’t as capable handle it. Allowing people to be challenged is usually when they grow the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-it-important&quot;&gt;Is it Important?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the thing someone asked from me really isn’t as important to them as I think it is. I have to ask them how important it is that I be the one to do it for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe they don’t even care about it anymore, or know of someone else who can do it in my place. I’ll never know unless I ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hold-your-ground&quot;&gt;Hold Your Ground&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, backing out of a commitment is akin to lighting a match that’ll burn a bridge. I have to be open to being the target for disappointment and hurt feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I also have be ready to share how the commitment is affecting important areas of my life. Maybe it’s even hurting the relationship between me and this person. I share this so the friendship doesn’t take a turn for the worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people will understand and be sympathetic to a plight if you’re stretched too thin, though some may not. Which ever the case, hold your ground. If you know you need to step down to protect yourself, do it with a clear conscience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, it’s important to guard our relationships and health closely. Once we’ve lightened the load, we need to start working on ways to say no when our ego tells us to say yes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jim Mitchell Media</name></author><summary type="html">No matter how well-intentioned we are, sometimes we allow things to sneak into our lives under the guise of it being something important.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Your First Dreamforce</title><link href="/2019/11/09/your-first-dreamforce/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Your First Dreamforce" /><published>2019-11-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-11-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/2019/11/09/your-first-dreamforce</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/09/your-first-dreamforce/">&lt;p&gt;Yay! It’s your first Dreamforce!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re pumped to finally be part of the magic. I bet you’ve already looked at a lot of other blogs to learn how to be ready before you landed here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are a few of my recommendations to make it a more memorable experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comfortable-shoes&quot;&gt;Comfortable Shoes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to wear comfortable shoes your feet are already used to, so don’t buy what you plan to wear a couple of days in advance. Take your old, ratty sneakers if you have to. I even recommend bringing two pair of super-comfy shoes if you can. Trust me, your feet will thank you for it. Having two pair of shoes helps reduce foot fatigue and keeps you feeling refreshed all around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll do a lot of walking over the four or five days of Dreamforce (I logged over 40 miles last year), and your dogs are going to be really tired by the end of the first day. Keeping foot-fresh should be one of your top priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring extra socks and change them during the day too. It’ll help, I promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;crowds-chaos-and-pandemonium&quot;&gt;Crowds, Chaos and Pandemonium&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumor has it Salesforce reduced the number of attendees this year compared to last. Even if this is true, be ready for plenty of chaos and pandemonium. The entire Dreamforce campus will be really crowded, with most people looking at their mobile device to figure out where they’re going next, so pack your patience along with those shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people will be friendly and some won’t. It’s just how it is. Deciding to be one of the friendly people now will go a long way to enjoying the whole experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to smile at other people and maybe even strike up a conversation with a stranger or two while standing in a line. You never know who you might meet by chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-overload-your-schedule&quot;&gt;Don’t Overload Your Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first year, I filled my schedule to the brim with all the great sessions I wanted to attend, and barely made half of them. Give yourself plenty of time to get to your next session. Remember; crowds, chaos and pandemonium, not just on the street, but in the hotels where sessions are held too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty minutes to get from one place to another is not nearly enough time unless those sessions are in the same hotel. Give yourself the time to get there and find a prime seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also have some empty time to just wander an area you’re interested in. The Admin, Developer or Expo halls have a lot to see. Having free time to stroll through them might open up some unexpected opportunities to learn something, or meet someone new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stay-hydrated-and-well-fed&quot;&gt;Stay Hydrated and Well Fed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s going to be easy to skip a meal or forget to drink water. Bring high-protein or complex carb, non-sugary snacks to keep the hangries at bay. It’ll go a long way to helping you retain the patience you’ll need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying hydrated will help reduce headaches and fatigue too. There will be water stations all over the place… Use them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-carry-a-laptop&quot;&gt;Don’t Carry a Laptop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you absolutely have to have it with you, leave your laptop at the hotel. I carried mine with me the first year I attended and only pulled it out of my bag once. It was more of a ball and chain than it was the tool I thought it would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, carry an analog journal to take notes, or have a good note-taking app on your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team will be using &lt;a href=&quot;https://quip.com&quot;&gt;Quip&lt;/a&gt; to share session notes with each other this year. The app is so good it’s earned a permanent place on my phone’s home screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-be-afraid-of-your-heroes&quot;&gt;Don’t Be Afraid of Your Heroes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you cross paths with someone from the community who inspires you, take the opportunity to introduce yourself to them. Naturally, be polite when doing it and respect any conversations your hero may already be involved in, but by introducing yourself, you could be opening the door to a friendship or opportunity further down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The community heroes are heroes for a reason – because they enjoy helping others learn and grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I crossed paths with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MikeGerholdt&quot;&gt;Mike Gerholdt&lt;/a&gt; very much by chance my first Dreamforce and was totally star-struck. I wish I’d taken a few more minutes to chat with him than I did. Don’t have the same regret I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say hello, thank them for inspiring you and ask them a few questions you’d like to know about them. Wrap it up by asking if you can connect with them on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keep-yourself-safe&quot;&gt;Keep Yourself Safe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many areas of San Francisco I’d call questionable when it comes to your safety, especially after dark. Don’t walk if you don’t have to. There will be plenty of Uber and Lyft in the city. Getting yourself into a questionable circumstance could be scary at best and harmful at worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Know your surroundings at all times and keep your head on a swivel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-lots-of-pictures&quot;&gt;Take Lots of Pictures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, take lots of pictures and share them with your friends and family, and on social media, using the #&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/DF19&quot;&gt;DF19 hashtag&lt;/a&gt;. Your pictures will remind you of the magic you experienced and keep you pumped through the year until you get to go to your next Dreamforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to connect with me through social media in the menu above and let me know you’ll be at Dreamforce. I may not be a hero, but I do love connecting with other people who have a passion for Salesforce like I do. I might even know someone who can help you out. You never know…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jim Mitchell Media</name></author><summary type="html">Yay! It’s your first Dreamforce!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Memorable Cigarettes</title><link href="/2018/07/28/memorable-cigarettes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Memorable Cigarettes" /><published>2018-07-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/2018/07/28/memorable-cigarettes</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/07/28/memorable-cigarettes/">&lt;p&gt;After nearly fifty years, I can still remember the first time I smoked a cigarette. It was early spring and my family lived on a farm in a semi-rural part of Colorado, a little north of Denver, at the foot of the Rocky Mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lived there with my mother, wicked step-father (I’m not even sure they were married, to be honest) and little half-sister. The closest kid my age lived more than five miles away, so I had no one to play with. This meant I had to find ways to keep myself entertained. Most of them ended up being things little boys are not supposed to do. Left to my own devices, it’s a wonder I lived through all of my escapades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was seven years old and had stolen a pack of my mom’s Kool Menthol 100s. I had a pack of matches from somewhere (yes, I was a pyro too, but that’s a post for another time) and thought I could smoke just like mom and wicked step-father did. After taking a pack from her carton in the refrigerator, I snuck outside and hid behind the juniper trees where I wouldn’t be seen. I opened the pack, took the long cigarette out, put it between my lips, struck a match, lit up and took a big puff like I’d seen the adults do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oddly enough, I wasn’t repulsed by the taste. In fact, I actually liked it. I still remember the menthol sensation on my tongue. It had a little bit of burn to it, but the taste wasn’t that bad. I felt very grown up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, my little boy brain didn’t know you should inhale the smoke from a cigarette, which is probably good because I’m sure if I had, I would have wound up puking my guts out behind the trees. Sometimes I wonder; if I had inhaled, would I have ended up picking up the habit nine years later, or would I have been turned off completely?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were other experiments with smoking through my childhood, but none really stuck. I’d smoke here and there and eventually lose interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until the day I met Tracy. He had just moved into the neighborhood where my mother, step-sister and I were living (wicked step-father was long-gone now). I think he said he was from New York. He was my age but had already become a pack-a-day smoker. I vividly recall the summer evening he offered me a Marlboro Red from his hard pack box. You weren’t cool if you smoked soft pack, you know. It had to be hard pack and it had to be Marlboro Reds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began taking him up on his offers of free cigarettes. Before I knew it, I was smoking every day, bumming cigarettes from friends whenever I could. Then the moment I knew I was hooked came: I wanted to smoke while I was alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mother, being the spectacular parent she was, started buying my smokes for me, so I had a steady supply of my own stashed in the refrigerator. Her rationale was that she’d rather I smoke openly instead of hiding it. I think she hoped I’d come to hate the habit and give up. Well, thanks mom, that didn’t quite work out as planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So at the tender age of sixteen, I became a confirmed pack-a-day smoker. All the other kids my age were doing it, so why not me too? The problem was, I really liked smoking. I knew I wasn’t going to stop. Other kids did it to be cool. I did it to feed the nicotine addiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twelve years went by, and then I met Pam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still see the moment from our very first date in my mind’s eye. We were running across a busy street in downtown Santa Monica to get to the club where we were headed to see a band. In the middle of the street, the hard pack of Marlboro Lights fell to the ground from my shirt pocket with a loud &lt;em&gt;plop&lt;/em&gt; sound. I bent down and picked them up. When we got to the sidewalk on the other side, she immediately told me “&lt;em&gt;I don’t date people who smoke.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a punch to the face, but one I’m glad I took. Naturally, I didn’t light up on that date, or any other we had after that. We’re still married 25 years later and she’s my best friend. I made the choice to quit because of her and I’m proud to say I haven’t smoked a cigarette since before we were engaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can remember a bunch of different cigarettes I smoked through my life, but thanks to someone who is very special to me, I can’t remember the very last one. For that, I’m forever grateful.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jim Mitchell Media</name></author><summary type="html">After nearly fifty years, I can still remember the first time I smoked a cigarette. It was early spring and my family lived on a farm in a semi-rural part of Colorado, a little north of Denver, at the foot of the Rocky Mountains.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Ant Mound</title><link href="/2018/07/28/the-ant-mound/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ant Mound" /><published>2018-07-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/2018/07/28/the-ant-mound</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/07/28/the-ant-mound/">&lt;p&gt;One of my earliest childhood memories is traumatic, at least what would seem traumatic to a three-and-a-half-year-old little boy. Though it didn’t turn out to be the end of the world, it sure seemed like a living hell when it happened. I still carry the memory with me a half-century later, so it damaged me on some level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My family – mother, wicked step-father, newborn baby sister and myself – were living in an old two-story house in Lancaster, California, which in the late 1960s was still mostly desert scrub and Joshua trees. We were located far enough away from everything else that it could be called the middle of nowhere. Today, a strip mall stands where the house once did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were so remote that my mother didn’t really pay attention to what I was getting into. She trusted I would not stray too far and everything would just work itself out. She had a newborn baby to worry about and didn’t give me as much attention as I probably should have gotten. With nothing to do and no watchful eye, I would wander the acre-sized property, trying to keep myself entertained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, I decided I would make friends with the ants who had built a nest out in the open area behind the house. I remember being fascinated by how they scurried back and forth, some appearing from the mound while others disappeared into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make friends with them, it seemed logical I had to get close and be down on their level. This meant I had to sit next to the mound. So I planted myself there on the ground, wearing my tan little boy shorts, a striped t-shirt and little red sneakers. When the first few ants crawled on me, I thought they were welcoming my invitation of friendship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind you, these were not your garden variety ants. They where those red and black kind that are almost a quarter of an inch long with strong mandibles. These ants were big, fast, and it turns out, very aggressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I knew it, I was covered by dozens of ants that saw me as a threat to their home. The hive mind sounded the alarm and went on the attack. First, I felt one bite, then a few more and several more soon after that. Suddenly, my skin was on fire as the big red and black ants bit me over and over. They were everywhere on my body from head to toe. No matter how hard I tried, I couldn’t get them off me. This was pain unlike any other in my short time on this earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a panic, I got up from the ground and began stripping my clothes off as I ran toward the house screaming like a banshee. By the time I got to the back door, I was completely naked except for my shoes, covered with big red welts everywhere. I ran upstairs where I found my mother nursing my half-sister. I’m sure the sight of her little boy bursting into the room in his birthday suit with tears streaming down his face freaked her out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was able to settle me down enough to get the story out of me. She squished the few remaining ants she found in my hair, then broke out the ointment to soothe the angry, swollen bites. Her motherly attention dissolved my anxiety and I was able to calm down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many times my mother and I reminisced about that mishap over the years. We even talked about it the last time I saw her before she passed away. She always thought it was hilarious. I, on the other hand, have a different take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this day, ants give me the heebie-jeebies – even the small black ones you see after leaving greasy or sugary food out. If I find even one ant crawling on me after sitting in the grass, I’ll panic and start doing a wild – and very unmanly – arm-flailing dance to get the critter off me as fast as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a big lesson that day… Don’t sit on an ant mound without knowing the consequences, because you may end up being eaten alive. It was the last time I did.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jim Mitchell Media</name></author><summary type="html">One of my earliest childhood memories is traumatic, at least what would seem traumatic to a three-and-a-half-year-old little boy. Though it didn’t turn out to be the end of the world, it sure seemed like a living hell when it happened. I still carry the memory with me a half-century later, so it damaged me on some level.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Start Somewhere</title><link href="/2018/07/27/start-somewhere/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Start Somewhere" /><published>2018-07-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/2018/07/27/start-somewhere</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/07/27/start-somewhere/">&lt;p&gt;Eventually you use up every excuse in your book for not doing the thing you keep saying you’re going to do. You’ve procrastinated yourself into a corner and realize it’s either time to just do it, or finally forget about it and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s me, sometimes…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had this blog for nearly 14 years. In all that time, I only have 11 posts to show for it. That’s less than one post per year, with the newest one being more than a year old. At one point, I had written dozens of posts. But like any good artist is prone to doing, I trashed most of them because I felt like they were fodder. I regret making that choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seriously slacked in my writing since, which is sad, because I’ve always enjoyed the process. To me, putting words down, then moving them around to communicate an idea is fun. When I get into a flow, the words come out and land on the page. I don’t have to struggle with what I’m trying to say. They’re just there all of a sudden. When I tell a story through my writing, I feel like I’ve created this thing that lives and breathes on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be truthful, I made a fatal mistake a few years back. Struggling to find my own voice, I began modeling my work after what other people were doing. However, since it wasn’t &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; voice, I began to believe what I had to say didn’t make a difference, so why should I even bother? This grew into the worst case of writer’s block there ever was in the history of man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, probably not. I’m sure there have been worse cases by far better writers, but I became so utterly uninspired to write during the last five years that it literally hurt to even &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; about putting words down. The three posts I made in 2018 were not easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make up for my lack of creativity, I found a great way to procrastinate – tweaking my WordPress theme about a hundred-gazillion times. It became all-consuming to get things just pixel perfect and then start over from scratch again. I’ve written and tweaked more CSS code than I’m willing to admit, though I have gotten pretty good at it. My site theme is practically everything I’ve ever imagined in my head at this point. I can’t improve on it much more, if at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do I do now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now is the time to stop procrastinating and make something. It doesn’t require perfection. My work will get better with practice. It doesn’t need to have meaning or impart some deep zen-like wisdom to the reader. I just need to start getting the stuff in my head out into written word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here and now is the best place for it, so this is where I’ve decided to begin again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have you been putting off? Is now the time for you to start again too?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jim Mitchell Media</name></author><summary type="html">Eventually you use up every excuse in your book for not doing the thing you keep saying you’re going to do. You’ve procrastinated yourself into a corner and realize it’s either time to just do it, or finally forget about it and move on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Eliminating Digital Distractions</title><link href="/2017/04/13/eliminating-digital-distractions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eliminating Digital Distractions" /><published>2017-04-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-04-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/2017/04/13/eliminating-digital-distractions</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2017/04/13/eliminating-digital-distractions/">&lt;p&gt;Life is so full of distractions. It seems everything is vying for our attention in one way or another these days, with most of it coming from our electronic gadgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take time to look up from your phone for a few minutes, you’ll find a sea of humanity with faces buried in their own device. It’s painful to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’ve come to a point where I’ve had it with the digital distractions in my life, so this is what I’ve done about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-removed-the-useless-apps-from-my-phone&quot;&gt;I Removed the Useless Apps from My Phone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a time I had more than four screens of apps on my iPhone. I know many people who have far more than that. I don’t know how they manage all those screens since I could barely cope with the number I had. I’d regularly forget where an app was, which would usually be somewhere on the third screen, beyond two other screens of mostly unused apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I wasn’t aware of it, I’d made a game out of shuffling apps around on my home screens, hoping to one day land on the perfect combination that made perfect sense and put the universe back in order. Honestly, I think most of the apps on my phone back then got moved around more often than they were ever used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this dawned on me, I decided it was time to purge. The first order of business was to get rid of the useless time-wasting “social” apps. I removed them from my phone without hesitation, deciding if I want to spend time on Facebook, I’ll make time specifically for it. Now, I’m lucky if I look at the site more than three or four times a month. I don’t miss Facebook and could probably go without it entirely if I decided to. I only keep it around to stay in touch with extended family and old friends. I intentionally pared my “friend” list down to less than 50 people that I actually know too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After nuking the useless apps, I started an experiment with the remaining by moving the ones I didn’t absolutely need to a “folder” on the second home screen. If I used an app more than a few times in a week, it got “unpacked” and promoted back to the first home screen. After a month of this, I ended up with just 16 apps on my first screen – including the four I’d left in the dock as “must-have” when I started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For apps that I didn’t touch after two months, I completely removed them from the phone. I know if I ever need a particular app, I can download it again — where it will find its rightful place on the second screen with all of the other lesser-used apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I evaluate my home screen every few weeks now to demote or remove apps if I feel they’re not serving a purpose. This has helped me stay laser-focused when I’m using my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-set-all-but-the-most-important-apps-to-a-badge-notification&quot;&gt;I Set All But the Most Important Apps to a Badge Notification&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the apps I keep on my phone, if I need to see a notification of some kind, I’ll set it to badge only. No sounds, vibrations, banners or alerts to distract me. I’ll check it on my schedule, thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This includes email — both personal and work. I purposely decided I didn’t want up to the moment email notifications, and I’ve found it quite liberating. Now, when I see a badge on an app, maybe I’ll look at it, maybe I won’t. It pretty much depends on the number displayed on the badge whether I decide to act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are exceptions to this rule, but they are few. The Phone app obviously needs notifications — otherwise, my phone isn’t a phone. Same for goes for Messages. I communicate with my immediate family by text a lot, so I leave this notification enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only other notifications I allow are OmniFocus for task management and Fantastical for calendars. I definitely need to be on time for meetings and appointments, and I must complete my tasks on time too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I turned on “Do Not Disturb” mode between the hours of 10pm and 6am — which is when I go to bed, and an hour after I get up. That first hour in the morning with no distractions helps me get focused on my day ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a notification junkie like I was, it’s hard to get used to working this way. But if you give it some time, you’ll find you’re picking your phone up a lot less and getting a lot more done during the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a try. You’ll feel less tethered to your phone, I promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-set-limits-on-use&quot;&gt;I Set Limits on Use&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a family, we’ve agreed to set limits on when and where electronic devices are acceptable. Never, ever can any one of us bring a phone to the table during a meal. This rule extends to restaurant outings too. Once a meal is on the table, all gadgets go away until after the last person finishes their meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we’re in a family setting for the holidays or a birthday, all devices get put away in pockets and purses so we can spend time socializing face-to-face. It’s okay if a phone comes out for a photo or two, but if any family member gets caught zoning out on their phone, everyone else reminds them of the rule. It’s worked pretty well so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some of the ways I’ve started breaking the twitch to reach for my phone and check it. Sometimes I forget, but I find every day gets a little easier. If you’re looking to lessen your own digital distractions, give some of these a try yourself. You might find there’s a lot more going on around you than you realized.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jim Mitchell Media</name></author><summary type="html">Life is so full of distractions. It seems everything is vying for our attention in one way or another these days, with most of it coming from our electronic gadgets.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Saying No</title><link href="/2017/03/12/saying-no/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Saying No" /><published>2017-03-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-03-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/2017/03/12/saying-no</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2017/03/12/saying-no/">&lt;p&gt;Saying no can be one of the hardest things to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No to an exciting new project. No to a volunteer opportunity in the community or at church; no to the extra helping of food at a meal; no to bad habits we’ve carried around with us all our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s tremendous power in saying no. When we have the courage to do it, we stop stretching ourselves too thin. We make more time for our families. We become healthier by defeating the temptation to eat the extra cookie. We break bad habits that have held us captive all our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These small wins add up over time and give us the courage to say no when we should more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s okay to say no. It doesn’t mean you’re weak. It says you’re strong and willing to sacrifice for the important stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes guts to say no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m working hard to learn this habit. No extra projects; no outside distractions and commitments that burn me out and take me away from the family; no to using food to deal with stress; no to procrastination; no wasting time on things that don’t matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found it’s not easy. The temptation to give in is always there. I have to remind myself almost every day: “&lt;em&gt;Is this thing worth what it’s going to take away from something else?&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m able to stay the course, I make room for plenty of yes in my life. Yes to spending time with family and friends; yes to being more focused and in the moment; yes to being mindful of those around me; yes to being tolerant of others; yes to making my health a priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes a lot of effort to say no. But in the end the good that comes from it far outweighs the bad we’re able to leave behind.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jim Mitchell Media</name></author><summary type="html">Saying no can be one of the hardest things to do.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spin Cycle</title><link href="/2017/03/07/spin-cycle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spin Cycle" /><published>2017-03-07T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-03-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>/2017/03/07/spin-cycle</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2017/03/07/spin-cycle/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been around long enough to know life moves in cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that were new and exciting one day eventually become dull and boring the next. The pursuit of shiny objects and interesting paths quickly fall by the wayside before you realize it. We move from one thing to the next and then another in search of a quick thrill, because we’ve become instant gratification junkies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if, instead, we intentionally slowed our lives down? What if we deliberately chose to look at the world in wonder like we did when we were young? What if we took time out to play like we did when we were children? What if we stopped to listen to what’s going on inside instead of burying our faces in smart devices that make us dumb?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spend our adult lives working, chasing dreams, and running after material possessions we think will make us happy. But let me ask you; in all of your pursuits, are you truly content?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is your soul really at peace?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s any hint of hesitation in your answer, it might be time to step back, take a look at the bigger picture, and find what really fulfills you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your time on this pale blue dot is finite. It would be a tragic waste to get to the end and say “&lt;em&gt;I wish I could have…&lt;/em&gt;” Maybe today should be the day you stop spinning cycles on unnecessary things that don’t matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choice is yours. It has been all along.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jim Mitchell Media</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been around long enough to know life moves in cycles.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Top Chrome Extensions Every Salesforce Admin Needs</title><link href="/2016/08/18/top-chrome-extensions-every-salesforce-admin-needs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top Chrome Extensions Every Salesforce Admin Needs" /><published>2016-08-18T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-08-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/2016/08/18/top-chrome-extensions-every-salesforce-admin-needs</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2016/08/18/top-chrome-extensions-every-salesforce-admin-needs/">&lt;p&gt;Most Salesforce admins have a list of favorite Google Chrome extensions they use to make their work just a little easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I’m all about being as productive as I can possibly be, these are my top picks of the ones I regularly use to add just a tiny bit of time back into my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/salesforce-admin-check-al/efcahpjiijlbojmfmaceicchnhkgdkje&quot;&gt;Salesforce Admin Check All&lt;/a&gt; – Have a long list of fields to check in a profile to enable visibility and/or edit-ability? This one is a total life (and time) saver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/salesforce-change-set-ass/halgnjjpjodohklhpacagljceggiiplf&quot;&gt;Salesforce Change Set Assistant&lt;/a&gt; – Why the functionality this extension adds to building change sets is not native I’ll never know, but it makes creating those change sets with hundreds of items a heck of a lot faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/salesforce-schema-builder/mhmpcpfhhfdoeiejndcmogmnlomkfdkk&quot;&gt;Salesforce.com Schema Builder Expander&lt;/a&gt; – Want more room to work in schema builder when using a smaller screen? This extension hides the wasted header space so you see more on the canvas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/salesforcecom-id-clipper/hfiffenhnefppjhloglpebefjlbhoeai&quot;&gt;Salesforce.com Id Clipper&lt;/a&gt; – Just like the name says, clip any Id of any record you’re on, including RecoryTypeId, ProfileId, and RoleId. I use this one at least 10 times a day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/columncopy/lapbbfoohlcmlbdaakldmmallcbcbpjb&quot;&gt;ColumnCopy&lt;/a&gt; – I use this to build quick lists of fields from objects in order to share their API names for integrations, to make spreadsheets of elements in a change set, and anywhere else I want a copy of the html table I’m viewing. Works outside of Salesforce too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/salesforcecom-quick-login/dccccilgophpadpomgajjlkkioipoojh&quot;&gt;Salesforce.com Quick Login As&lt;/a&gt; – As an admin, I have to login as users all the time to help troubleshoot their issues. I love being able to do it from the menu bar instead of slogging my way into the Setup area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/salesforcecom-sandbox-fav/nkfllgjejgfgcddfccnijhndhdmjkamf&quot;&gt;Salesforce.com Sandbox Favicon Extension&lt;/a&gt; – I spend most of my day working in sandboxes creating new solutions. When a user calls for support, I have to jump into production to help them out. This extension prevents me from making changes in the wrong org once I’m done helping them out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/salesforce1-simulator/cknbjckicenodbiaejbmkjhldffonggp&quot;&gt;Salesforce1 Simulator&lt;/a&gt; – When you want to show off what Salesforce1 looks like, or troubleshoot a mobile issue, this one’s the bomb. I’ve impressed more than one C-level exec with this. There’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/salesforce1-sandbox-simul/mgknkgnenlhghpfpdcohmgiejlcaapih&quot;&gt;sandbox&lt;/a&gt; version too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These Chrome extensions save me at least a couple of hours a week, if not more — not to mention reducing the likelihood of a mistake, which is even more costly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What extensions do you use to make your Salesforce admin life better?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jim Mitchell Media</name></author><summary type="html">Most Salesforce admins have a list of favorite Google Chrome extensions they use to make their work just a little easier.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Passing Your Salesforce Adm201 Certification Exam</title><link href="/2014/10/15/passing-your-salesforce-adm201-certification-exam/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Passing Your Salesforce Adm201 Certification Exam" /><published>2014-10-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-10-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>/2014/10/15/passing-your-salesforce-adm201-certification-exam</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2014/10/15/passing-your-salesforce-adm201-certification-exam/">&lt;p&gt;I passed the Salesforce ADM201 certification exam today. It’s been a five-year road to get here. From the first week I began working with Salesforce, I decided attaining certification was something I wanted to pursue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve done it, I thought it might be good to share the things that helped me be successful with those looking to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;know-your-stuff&quot;&gt;Know Your Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your success or failure pretty much boils down to this… You’ve got to know your stuff or it’s never going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Salesforce ADM201 certification exam is not a walk in the park. You’ll never pass it by just reading the online help, or taking online practice tests and studying flash cards — most of which are badly outdated, or just plain wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re going to need to be familiar with just about every area of Salesforce and how it actually works — where and how you can do something, and where and why you can’t do something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means getting a developer org and configuring it just like you would if you were doing it for your day job or a client. Be creative in your approach. Try doing things you’ve never done. Try to break it. Enter real data and learn how it flows through the system from a Campaign to a converted Lead to a resolved Case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn it, live it, be it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do everything in your power to wrap your head around the big picture of what Salesforce does and totally understand it. That’s what being a good admin is all about anyway — knowing what can or can’t be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;study-with-a-group&quot;&gt;Study With a Group&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t stress this one enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My employer was kind enough to purchase a year of Premiere Plus Support in order to provide me the online courses to pursue certification, and I did all 60+ hours of both the ADM201 and DEV401 trainings. I learned a lot from it, but it wasn’t until I joined a study group that the learning really sank in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaborating with a group of your peers introduces fresh ideas, which could give you a completely different perspective about a topic. That, in turn, leads to other moments of discovery. If you’re serious about earning a certification, I suggest you find others who are as committed as you to passing your exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined the Salesforce Certification Study Group in the Salesforce Success Community. Deepa Patel and the others who volunteer with the group have worked hard to develop a successful curriculum with a high passing rate for those who are committed enough to make it to the end. It doesn’t cost any more than your time and effort, plus the $200 to register for your Salesforce ADM201 certification exam, which you’re going to spend anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re accepted into the private group, watch what goes on in the Chatter feed for a while, then when signups for the next round of sessions are announced, join the one that best suits your geographical region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-the-time&quot;&gt;Make the Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay. You’ve been accepted into the study group. But if you aren’t totally serious about earning your certification, you’ll never be successful. Period. You’ve got to want it to happen. If you don’t give studying the attention it needs, you can forget about passing, and may as well stop reading now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make it what you think about when you’re sitting in traffic, brushing your teeth, or taking a shower. Turn off the TV for a couple hours each night and learn something new about Salesforce instead. Choose to become obsessed for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you end up joining the certification study group, make time to do the work you’re supposed to do before the next session — every single week. Commit to the 15 weeks the group is going to require from you. Be ready to demo your work for the online sessions. Know exactly what you did, why you did it, and have a reason for it. I promise you’ll learn incredible amounts if you commit to working this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-real-with-yourself&quot;&gt;Be Real with Yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be 100% honest with yourself. Ask yourself “Am I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; ready to pursue certification?” If you’ve only been working with Salesforce a few months, it’s going to be a tough row to hoe, even with the help and support of a study group — who may not be too keen helping you along while studying themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being part of a group requires commitment. People are depending on you to have ideas that could be different than theirs. Are you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; ready to commit to a group of 6-12 people for 15 weeks, and collaborate with them? Are you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; ready to do 5 to 8 hours of homework each week? It’s going to take serious sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not ready, then wait until you are. You have a better chance of succeeding if you do. By joining the study group without enough experience, chances are you’ll fall behind fast, which is going to discourage you. Don’t set yourself up to fail. Be ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-good-resources&quot;&gt;Use Good Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned the online tests and flash cards earlier. Don’t rely on them at all. Salesforce adds lots of new features at each release. Flash cards and tests from the Spring ’11 release are full of misinformation now. If you rely on them to know your stuff, you might not know much at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one good resource I’ll personally endorse, and that’s John Coppedge’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://certifiedondemand.com/&quot;&gt;Certified On Demand&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined while John was developing the site, but would have no hesitation spending the $40 lifetime membership that he’s asking for now. It’s a good resource that’s kept current. The questions he’s developed are quite similar to the real test (but not actual questions, and are just a little easier).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider supporting John’s efforts and buying a lifetime membership. Use Certified On Demand as a supplement to studying with the Salesforce Certification Study Group. It helped me be confident I was ready when I started doubting myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only other resource you need now is to watch the Dreamforce Get Started on the Certified Administrator Credential workshop video. It provides solid advice for being ready, how to take the Salesforce ADM201 certification exam, and knowing what you’re walking into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;taking-your-exam&quot;&gt;Taking Your Exam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve scheduled your test, and now it’s time to go take it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s only one thing to be said… Know that you know what you know. If you’ve worked hard in the Salesforce Certification Study Group, you’re ready to pass. Walk into the exam knowing that fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you sit down to begin, take a minute to breathe and relax. Then start your exam using the techniques you learned from the workshop video. Before you know it, you’ll be waking out of the testing center as a Salesforce Certified Administrator.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jim Mitchell Media</name></author><summary type="html">I passed the Salesforce ADM201 certification exam today. It’s been a five-year road to get here. From the first week I began working with Salesforce, I decided attaining certification was something I wanted to pursue.</summary></entry></feed>